Finding Aid for Thomas M. Cooley Papers 1850-1898
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Thomas M. Cooley Papers 1850-1898
Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1824-1898.
851316 Aa 2
Professor of Law and American History at the University of Michigan, Michigan Supreme Court Justice, and chairman of the Interstate Commerce Commission. Papers include correspondence, diaries, lectures, notes and photographs.
9 linear feet
1 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was transferred from the William L. Clements Library (donor no. 1333 ).
The collection is open for research.
Cooley's diaries, 1887-1894, and his lectures on government are also available on microfilm.
Thomas McIntyre Cooley was born in Attica, N. Y. on January 6, 1824. In 1842, after having graduated from the Attica Academy, Cooley began the study of law in Palmyra, N. Y. He came to Adrian, Mich., in September, 1843 where he completed his law studies with the firm of Tiffany & Beaman. He was admitted to the bar in January, 1846. He briefly practice law in Tecumseh, then returned to Adrian in 1848 becoming member of the firm of Beaman, Beecher & Cooley. In 1855, he formed a partnership with Charles M. Croswell.
In 1857 Cooley was chosen by the Michigan legislature to compile the laws of the State. In January, 1858, he was appointed reporter of the Supreme Court, and while in that position edited and published eight volumes of reports. In 1859, with the establishment of the Law Department of the University of Michigan, Cooley was chosen, along with Judge J. V. Campbell and C. I. Walker, to be one of the three professors in the new department.
In 1864 Cooley was elected a Justice of the Supreme Court, and was re-elected in 1869 and in 1877, continuing in that position until his defeat in 1885. During this same period he continued his teaching and writing. In 1884, he resigned his professorship in the law department to accept the position of professor of American history and constitutional law in the Literary Department of the University of Michigan.
In the mid-1880s, Cooley became involved as an arbitrator in disputes involving the railroad. In 1887, President Cleveland appointed Cooley to the newly organized Interstate Commerce Commission, where he served as chairman. He served for four years resigning in September 1891. He died in Ann Arbor, Michigan, September 12, 1898.
The Thomas M. Cooley papers are arranged in six series
Correspondence, 1846-1898
Biographical and estate material
Diaries
Miscellaneous Papers and Scrapbooks
University of Michigan
Photographs
The Thomas McIntyre Cooley papers document the life and career of an attorney, jurist, teacher, scholar, and public official. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence received. A comprehensive calendar of these letters has been compiled by Virginia Ehrlicher in her doctoral thesis Thomas McIntyre Cooley: a calendar of his papers, 1846-1898. This three volume calendar is an important tool in accessing names of correspondents and topics covered. The remainder of the collection includes diaries, speeches, scrapbooks, course notes from some of his classes taught at the University of Michigan, and a scattering of photographs.
Subjects:
Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1824-1898.; Michigan--Politics and government--1845-1860.; Michigan--Politics and government--1861-1865.; Michigan--Politics and government--1866-1876.; Michigan--Politics and government--1877-1898.; Michigan. Supreme Court.; Republican Party (Mich.); United States. Interstate Commerce Commission.; United States--Politics and government--1845-1861.; United States--Politics and government--1861-1865.; United States--Politics and government--1865-1900.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); University of Michigan. Dept. of Political Science.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Law.; University of Michigan. President.; Coeducation--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students.
Contributors:
Alger, R. A. (Russell Alexander), 1836-1907.; Angell, Alexis C. (Alexis Caswell), 1857-1932.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Begole, Joshua Williams, 1815-1896.; Blair, Austin, 1818-1894.; Campbell, James V. (James Valentine), 1823-1890.; Champlin, John Wayne, 1831-1901.; Chaney, Henry A.; Christiancy, G. C.; Christiancy, Isaac Peckham, 1812-1890.; Clements, James.; Clute, Lemuel.; Cooley, Charles Horton, 1864-1929.; Cooley, Edgar Arthur.; Cooley, Eugene, 1849-1937.; Cullom, Shelby Moore, 1829-1914.; Dabney, W. D.; Dickinson, Donald McDonald, 1846-1917.; Dunn, Jacob Piatt, 1855-1924.; Ford, William F.; Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908.; Hitchcock, Henry, 1829-1902.; Hoar, George Frisbie, 1826-1904.; Hopkins, Charles Clark, b. 1849.; Hubbard, Fred S.; Jerome, David Howell, 1829-1896.; Kent, Charles A. (Charles Artemis), 1835-1917.; Kinne, Edward DeWitt, 1842-1921.; Kirchner, Otto, 1846-1920.; Lamont, Daniel Scott, 1851-1905.; Marston, Isaac, 1839-1891.; Meddaugh, Elijah Wood, 1833-1903.; Morrison, William Ralls, 1825-1909.; Moseley, Edward Augustus, 1846-1911.; O'Brien, Thomas James, 1842-1933.; Rogers, Henry Wade, 1853-1926.; Sawyer, Andrew Jackson, b. 1834.; Schoonmaker, Augustus.; Seligman, Edwin Robert Anderson, 1861-1939.; Underwood, W. A.; Van Zile, Philip T. (Philip Taylor), 1843-1917.; Walker, Aldace F., 1842-1901.; Washburn, William Drew, 1831-1912.; White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.; Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921.; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908.; Harrison, Benjamin, 1833-1901.; Pryor, Roger Atkinson, 1828-1919.; Seward, William Henry, 1839-1920.; Tappan, Henry Philip, 1805-1881.
Subjects - Visual Material
Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1824-1898.; Sculpture.
Genre/Form:
Diaries.; Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - Card index to correspondence (Box 9)
  - 1846-1850 (Box 1)
  - 1851 (Box 1)
  - 1852 (Box 1)
  - 1853-1862 (Box 1)
  - 1863-1864 (Box 1)
  - 1865-1868 (Box 1)
  - 1869-1870 (Box 1)
  - 1871
    - January-April 1871 (Box 1)
    - May-December 1871 (Box 1)
  - 1872 (Box 1)
  - 1873
    - January-June 1873 (Box 1)
    - July-December 1873 (Box 1)
  - 1874
    - January-June 1874 (Box 1)
    - July-December 1874 (Box 1)
  - 1875
    - January-July 1875 (Box 1)
    - August-December 1875 (Box 1)
  - 1876 (Box 1)
  - 1877 (Box 1)
  - 1878
    - January-April 1878 (Box 1)
    - May-July 1878 (Box 1)
    - August-September 1878 (Box 1)
    - October-December 1878 (Box 1)
  - 1879 (Box 1)
  - 1880 (Box 1)
  - 1881
    - January-March 1881 (Box 1)
    - April-May 15, 1881 (Box 1)
    - May 15-August 1881 (Box 1)
    - September-October 1881 (Box 1)
    - November 1881 (Box 1)
    - December 1-15, 1881 (Box 1)
    - December 16-31, 1881 (Box 1)
  - 1882
    - undated January 1-15, 1882 (Box 1)
    - January 16-31, 1882 (Box 1)
    - February 1-15, 1882 (Box 1)
    - February 16-28, 1882 (Box 1)
    - March 1-15, 1882 (Box 1)
    - March 16-31, 1882 (Box 1)
    - April 1-18, 1882 (Box 1)
    - April 19-30, 1882 (Box 1)
    - May 1-15, 1882 (Box 1)
    - May 16-31, 1882 (Box 1)
    - June 1-15, 1882 (Box 1)
    - June 16-30, 1882 (Box 1)
    - July 1-22, 1882 (Box 1)
    - July 23-31, 1882 (Box 1)
    - August 1-21, 1882 (Box 1)
    - August 22-31, 1882 (Box 1)
    - September 1-15, 1882 (Box 1)
    - September 16-30, 1882 (Box 1)
    - October 1-10, 1882 (Box 1)
    - October 11-31, 1882 (Box 1)
    - November 1-15, 1882 (Box 1)
    - November 16-30, 1882 (Box 1)
    - December 1-16, 1882 (Box 1)
    - December 17-31, 1882 (Box 1)
  - 1883
    - January 1-17, 1883 (Box 1)
    - January 18-31, 1883 (Box 1)
    - February 1-10, 1883 (Box 1)
    - February 11-16, 1883 (Box 1)
    - February 17-28, 1883 (Box 1)
    - March 16-31, 1883 (Box 1)
    - April-November 1883 (Box 1)
    - December 1-16, 1883 (Box 1)
    - December 17-31, 1883 (Box 1)
  - 1884
    - January 1-15, 1884 (Box 2)
    - January 16-31, 1884 (Box 2)
    - February 1-15, 1884 (Box 2)
    - February 16-28, 1884 (Box 2)
    - March 1-15, 1884 (Box 2)
    - March 16-31, 1884 (Box 2)
    - April 1-15, 1884 (Box 2)
    - April 16-30, 1884 (Box 2)
    - May 1-15, 1884 (Box 2)
    - May 16-31, 1884 (Box 2)
    - June 1-18, 1884 (Box 2)
    - June 19-30, 1884 (Box 2)
    - July 1-14, 1884 (Box 2)
    - July 15-31, 1884 (Box 2)
    - August 1884 (Box 2)
    - September 1-16, 1884 (Box 2)
    - September 17-30, 1884 (Box 2)
    - October 1-10, 1884 (Box 2)
    - October 11-31, 1884 (Box 2)
    - November 1-15, 1884 (Box 2)
    - November 16-30, 1884 (Box 2)
    - December 1-15, 1884 (Box 2)
    - December 16-30, 1884 (Box 2)
  - 1885
    - January 1-13, 1885 (Box 2)
    - January 14-31, 1885 (Box 2)
    - February 1-14, 1885 (Box 2)
    - February 15-21, 1885 (Box 2)
    - March 1-10, 1885 (Box 2)
    - March 11-18, 1885 (Box 2)
    - March 19-23, 1885 (Box 2)
    - March 24-26, 1885 (Box 2)
    - March 27-31, 1885 (Box 2)
    - April 1-9, 1885 (Box 2)
    - April 10-20, 1885 (Box 2)
    - April 21-30, 1885 (Box 2)
    - May 1-15, 1885 (Box 2)
    - May 16-31, 1885 (Box 2)
    - June 1-15, 1885 (Box 2)
    - June 16-30, 1885 (Box 2)
    - July 1-15, 1885 (Box 2)
    - July 16-30, 1885 (Box 2)
    - August 1-18, 1885 (Box 2)
    - August 19-31, 1885 (Box 2)
    - September 1-21, 1885 (Box 2)
    - September 22-30, 1885 (Box 2)
    - October 1-14, 1885 (Box 2)
    - October 15-31, 1885 (Box 2)
    - November 1-19, 1885 (Box 2)
    - November 21-30, 1885 (Box 2)
    - December 1-14, 1885 (Box 2)
    - December 15-31, 1885 (Box 2)
  - 1886
    - January 1-15, 1886 (Box 2)
    - January 16-31, 1886 (Box 2)
    - February 1-15, 1886 (Box 2)
    - February 16-28, 1886 (Box 2)
    - March 1-9, 1886 (Box 2)
    - March 10-20, 1886 (Box 2)
    - March 21-31, 1886 (Box 2)
    - April 1-15, 1886 (Box 3)
    - April 16-30, 1886 (Box 3)
    - May 1886 (Box 3)
    - June 1886 (Box 3)
    - July 1-9, 1886 (Box 3)
    - July 10-31, 1886 (Box 3)
    - August 1886 (Box 3)
    - September 1886 (Box 3)
    - October 1886 (Box 3)
    - November 1886 (Box 3)
    - December 1-15, 1886 (Box 3)
    - December 16-31, 1886 (Box 3)
  - 1887
    - 1887 undated (Box 3)
    - January 1-15, 1887 (Box 3)
    - January 16-31, 1887 (Box 3)
    - February 1-9, 1887 (Box 3)
    - February 10-20, 1887 (Box 3)
    - February 21-28, 1887 (Box 3)
    - March 1-13, 1887 (Box 3)
    - March 14-23, 1887 (Box 3)
    - March 24-31, 1887 (Box 3)
    - April 1-17, 1887 (Box 3)
    - April 18-30, 1887 (Box 3)
    - May 1-9, 1887 (Box 3)
    - May 10-21, 1887 (Box 3)
    - May 21-31, 1887 (Box 3)
    - June 1-11, 1887 (Box 3)
    - June 12-20, 1887 (Box 3)
    - July 1-19, 1887 (Box 3)
    - July 20-31, 1887 (Box 3)
    - August 1-9, 1887 (Box 3)
    - August 11-22, 1887 (Box 3)
    - August 23-31, 1887 (Box 3)
    - September 1-14, 1887 (Box 3)
    - September 15-30, 1887 (Box 3)
    - October 1-15, 1887 (Box 3)
    - October 16-31, 1887 (Box 3)
    - November 1-16, 1887 (Box 3)
    - November 17-30, 1887 (Box 3)
    - December 1887 (Box 3)
  - 1888
    - January 1-19, 1888 (Box 3)
    - January 20-31, 1888 (Box 3)
    - February 1-15, 1888 (Box 3)
    - February 16-28, 1888 (Box 3)
    - March 1-17, 1888 (Box 3)
    - March 18-25, 1888 (Box 3)
    - March 26-31, 1888 (Box 3)
    - April 1888 (Box 3)
    - May 1888 (Box 3)
    - June 1-6, 1888 (Box 3)
    - June 7-14, 1888 (Box 3)
    - June 15-30, 1888 (Box 3)
    - July 16-31, 1888 (Box 3)
    - August 1-19, 1888 (Box 3)
    - August 20-27, 1888 (Box 3)
    - August 28-31, 1888 (Box 3)
    - September 1-19, 1888 (Box 4)
    - September 20-30, 1888 (Box 4)
    - October 1-5, 1888 (Box 4)
    - October 6-14, 1888 (Box 4)
    - October 15-19, 1888 (Box 4)
    - October 20-31, 1888 (Box 4)
    - November 1-15, 1888 (Box 4)
    - November 16-30, 1888 (Box 4)
    - December 1-4, 1888 (Box 4)
    - December 5-12, 1888 (Box 4)
    - December 13-31, 1888 (Box 4)
  - 1889
    - January 1-11, 1889 (Box 4)
    - January 12-21, 1889 (Box 4)
    - January 22-31, 1889 (Box 4)
    - February 1-9, 1889 (Box 4)
    - February 10-18, 1889 (Box 4)
    - February 19-28, 1889 (Box 4)
    - March 1-19, 1889 (Box 4)
    - March 20-23, 1889 (Box 4)
    - March 24-31, 1889 (Box 4)
    - April 1-13, 1889 (Box 4)
    - April 14-30, 1889 (Box 4)
    - May 1-14, 1889 (Box 4)
    - May 15-31, 1889 (Box 4)
    - June 1-12, 1889 (Box 4)
    - June 13-18, 1889 (Box 4)
    - June 19-22, 1889 (Box 4)
    - June 23-30, 1889 (Box 4)
    - July 1-13, 1889 (Box 4)
    - July 15-21, 1889 (Box 4)
    - July 22-31, 1889 (Box 4)
    - August 1-11, 1889 (Box 4)
    - August 12-26, 1889 (Box 4)
    - August 27-31, 1889 (Box 4)
    - September 1-10, 1889 (Box 4)
    - September 11-16, 1889 (Box 4)
    - September 17-24, 1889 (Box 4)
    - September 25-30, 1889 (Box 4)
    - October 1-9, 1889 (Box 4)
    - October 10-23, 1889 (Box 4)
    - October 24-31, 1889 (Box 4)
    - November 1-21, 1889 (Box 4)
    - November 22-December 5, 1889 (Box 4)
    - December 6-15, 1889 (Box 4)
    - December 16-24, 1889 (Box 4)
    - December 25-31, 1889 (Box 4)
  - 1890
    - January 1890 (Box 4)
    - February 1-19, 1890 (Box 4)
    - February 10-17, 1890 (Box 4)
    - February 18-28, 1890 (Box 4)
    - March 2-19, 1890 (Box 4)
    - March 20-31, 1890 (Box 4)
    - April 1-9, 1890 (Box 4)
    - April 10-16, 1890 (Box 4)
    - April 17-30, 1890 (Box 4)
    - May 1-8, 1890 (Box 4)
    - May 9-17, 1890 (Box 4)
    - May 18-31, 1890 (Box 4)
    - June 1-18, 1890 (Box 4)
    - June 19-30, 1890 (Box 4)
    - July 1890 (Box 4)
    - August 1-20, 1890 (Box 4)
    - August 22-31, 1890 (Box 4)
    - September 1, 1890 (Box 4)
    - September 2, 1890 (Box 4)
    - September 3-18, 1890 (Box 4)
    - September 19-30, 1890 (Box 4)
    - October 1-20, 1890 (Box 4)
    - October 21-31, 1890 (Box 4)
    - December 1890 (Box 4)
  - 1891
    - 1891 undated (Box 5)
    - undated January 1-14, 1891 (Box 5)
    - January 14-26, 1891 (Box 5)
    - January 27-February 5, 1891 (Box 5)
    - February 6-23, 1891 (Box 5)
    - February 24-March 18, 1891 (Box 5)
    - April 1891 (Box 5)
    - May 1-12, 1891 (Box 5)
    - May 13-21, 1891 (Box 5)
    - May 22-31, 1891 (Box 5)
    - June 1891 (Box 5)
    - July 1-8, 1891 (Box 5)
    - July 9-31, 1891 (Box 5)
    - August 1891 (Box 5)
    - September 1-11, 1891 (Box 5)
    - September 5-30, 1891 (Box 5)
    - October 5-12, 1891 (Box 5)
    - October 13-November 6, 1891 (Box 5)
    - November 7-December 31, 1891 (Box 5)
  - 1892
    - January 1892 (Box 5)
    - February 1-5, 1892 (Box 5)
    - February 6-28, 1892 (Box 5)
    - March-April 1892 (Box 5)
    - May-September 10, 1892 (Box 5)
    - September 12-October 6, 1892 (Box 5)
    - October 7-31, 1892 (Box 5)
    - November 1-19, 1892 (Box 5)
    - November 20-December 31, 1892 (Box 5)
  - 1893
    - January 1-20, 1893 (Box 5)
    - January 21-March 5, 1893 (Box 5)
    - March 6-28, 1893 (Box 5)
    - March 29-April 12, 1893 (Box 5)
    - April 13-30, 1893 (Box 5)
    - May 1-June 5, 1893 (Box 5)
    - June 6-30, 1893 (Box 5)
    - July 3-24, 1893 (Box 5)
    - July 25-August 31, 1893 (Box 5)
    - September 1-12, 1893 (Box 5)
    - September 13-30, 1893 (Box 5)
    - October 1-17, 1893 (Box 5)
    - October 18-31, 1893 (Box 5)
    - November 1893 (Box 5)
    - December 1-19, 1893 (Box 5)
    - December 20-31, 1893 (Box 5)
  - 1894
    - Undated 1894 and January 1-14 1894 (Box 5)
    - January 15-31, 1894 (Box 5)
    - February 1-March 21, 1894 (Box 5)
    - March 22-31, 1894 (Box 5)
    - April 1-30, 1894 (Box 5)
    - May 1-10, 1894 (Box 5)
    - May 11-31, 1894 (Box 5)
    - June 1-16, 1894 (Box 5)
    - June 17-30, 1894 (Box 5)
    - July 1-12, 1894 (Box 5)
    - July 13-18, 1894 (Box 5)
    - July 19-31, 1894 (Box 5)
    - August 1894 (Box 5)
    - September 1894 (Box 5)
    - October 1894 (Box 5)
    - November 1894 (Box 5)
    - December 1894 (Box 5)
  - 1895
    - January 1895 (Box 5)
    - February 1895 (Box 5)
    - March 1895 (Box 5)
    - April 1895 (Box 5)
    - May-June 1895 (Box 5)
    - July-October 1895 (Box 5)
    - November-December 1895 (Box 5)
  - 1896
    - January-February 1896 (Box 5)
    - March-May 1896 (Box 5)
    - June-December 1896 (Box 5)
  - 1897 (Box 5)
  - 1898 (Box 5)
- Typescripts of correspondence
  - 1841-1869 (Box 6)
  - 1870-1871 (Box 6)
  - 1872 (Box 6)
  - 1873 (Box 6)
  - 1874 (Box 6)
  - 1875 (Box 6)
  - 1876 (Box 6)
  - 1877 (Box 6)
  - 1878 (Box 6)
  - 1879 (Box 6)
  - 1880 (Box 6)
  - 1881 (Box 6)
  - January 16-June 1882 (Box 6)
  - July 1882-February 1883 (Box 6)
  - March 1-15, 1883 (Box 6)
  - March 1883-May 1884 (Box 6)
  - July 1884-January 1885 (Box 6)
  - February-June 1885 (Box 6)
  - July-December 1885 (Box 6)
  - January-February 1886 (Box 6)
  - March-December 1886 (Box 6)
  - January-May 1887 (Box 6)
  - June-December 1887 (Box 6)
  - Typescripts, unsorted (Box 6)
- Biographical and estate papers
  - Obituaries 1898 (Box 6)
  - Cooley estate papers 1899-1936, 21 folders (Box 6)
  - Miscellanea (Box 6)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 6)
- Diaries
  - Diary 1887-1888 (Box 7)
    [microfilm available]
    [original and typescript copy]
  - Diary 1888-1889 (Box 7)
  - Diary 1889-1890 (Box 7)
  - Personal memoranda 1879-1894 (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous papers and Scrapbooks
  - Addresses and papers, 2 volumes (Box 7)
  - Lectures on City Government (Box 7)
  - Notes on Bryce's The American Commonwealth (Box 7)
  - First Annual Report of the Interstate Commerce Commission 1887 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook circa 1861-1898 (Volume 1)
    (including newspaper clippings and letters of Austin Blair, November 1861; Zachariah Chandler, September 1861; B.F. Granger, March 1861)
    (Located at Ac)
  - Scrapbook 1887-1898 (Box 8)
    (including clippings and correspondence)
  - Scrapbook of poetry and miscellanea 1858, undated (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook relating to 250th anniversary of Harvard College 1886 (Box 8)
  - Clippings of newspaper reviews of Michigan, A History of Governments 1885 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous speeches (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous announcements, invitations, programs, etc. (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous Cooley family material (Box 8)
    [found in papers of L.G. Vander Velde]
  - Photostats of miscellaneous newspaper articles (Box 8)
- University of Michigan
  - Course notes
    - U.S. Constitutional History (Box 8)
    - The Government of Cities (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, re: Michigan University dinner 1882 (Box 8)
    (includes card index to this correspondence)
- Photographs
  - Photographs (Box 8)
Selective Index to Correspondents
Alger, R. A. (Russell Alexander), 1836-1907.
1885-1886
Angell, Alexis C. (Alexis Caswell), 1857-1932.
1880-1891
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
1873-1902
Begole, Joshua Williams, 1815-1896.
1883
Blair, Austin, 1818-1894.
1861-1892
Champlin, John Wayne, 1831-1901.
[18 letters scattered throughout]
Chaney, Henry A.
[Throughout]
Christiancy, Isaac Peckham, 1812-1890.
[37 letters scattered throughout]
Clements, James.
[12 letters scattered throughout]
Clute, Lemuel
1882-1889
Cooley, Charles Horton, 1864-1929.
1900-1927
Cooley, Edgar Arthur.
1884-1897
Cooley, Eugene, 1849-1937.
1865-1912
Cullom, Shelby Moore, 1829-1914.
Feb. 22, 1886
Dabney, W. D.
1884-1895
Dickinson, Donald McDonald, 1846-1917.
1884-1895
Dunn, Jacob Piatt, 1855-1924.
[10 letters scattered throughout]
Ford, William F.
1881-1884
Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908.
[15 letters scattered throughout]
Hitchcock, Henry, 1829-1902.
[11 letters scattered throughout]
Hoar, George Frisbie, 1826-1904.
[3 letters scattered throughout]
Hopkins, Charles Clark, b. 1849.
1882-1889
Hubbard, Fred S.
1884-1895
Jerome, David Howell, 1829-1896.
[14 letters scattered throughout]
Kent, Charles A. (Charles Artemis), 1835-1917.
1881-1888
Kinne, Edward DeWitt, 1842-1921.
[13 letters scattered throughout]
Kirchner, Otto, 1846-1920.
[15 letters scattered throughout]
Lamont, Daniel Scott, 1851-1905.
[6 letters scattered throughout]
Marston, Isaac, 1839-1891.
[48 letters scattered throughout]
Meddaugh, Elijah Wood, 1833-1903.
1882-1889
Moseley, Edward Augustus, 1846-1911.
1884-1895
Moseley, Edward Augustus
1884-1895
O'Brien, Thomas James, 1842-1933.
1882-1889
Rogers, Henry Wade, 1853-1926.
1882-1894
Sawyer, Andrew Jackson, b. 1834.
[Throughout]
Schoonmaker, Augustus.
1884-1895
Seligman, Edwin Robert Anderson, 1861-1939.
[10 letters scattered throughout]
Underwood, W. A.
1882-1889
Van Zile, Philip T. (Philip Taylor), 1843-1917.
1882-1889
Walker, Aldace F., 1842-1901.
1884-1895
Washburn, William Drew, 1831-1912.
[8 letters scattered throughout]
White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.
[7 letters scattered throughout, including letter of June 5, 1871, relating to co-education]